Guide to the Maurice Hindus papers M2002
Special Collections and University Archives, Colgate University Libraries
- Articles, short manuscripts, interviews, and speeches, 1925-1968
  - Persia, undated, 1948
    - Hindus, "Pahlevi" - PERSIA #5, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Hindus, "Tabriz" - PERSIA #6, no year August 17, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Hindus, Unidentified pages 10-15 on Persia - PERSIA #7, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Hindus, "Bandit Story" - PERSIA #9, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Hindus, "Village" - PERSIA #10, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Siberia, undated
    - Hindus, "Siberia" - SIBERIA #1, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Hindus on Siberia - SIBERIA #2, undated; 8 pages (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Hindus-Sibera (pages 4-9) - SIBERIA #3, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Hindus, "The Triumph of Siberia and the Factory" - SIBERIA #4, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Hindus, Siberia and Canada - SIBERIA #5, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1939
    - Hindus, "Czechs' Tough Character" - CZECH #1, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Hindus, "Christmas Eve Czechoslovakia" - CZECH #2, 1939; 2 items (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Hindus, "The Funeral in Czechoslovakia" - CZECH #3, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Hindus, "Gunnar Almstedt," Czechoslovakia - CZECH #4, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Hindus, "Getting Married," Czechoslovakia - CZECH #5, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Hindus, "Schools," Czechoslovakia - CZECH #6, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Poland, undated
    - Hindus, Speech on Cracow, Poland - POLAND #1, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Hindus, Gdynia, Poland - POLAND #2, undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Russia, 1925-1962
    - Hindus, "The Meaning of Russia's Nationalism" - RUSSIA #5, 1943 July 15 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "Russia in Transition" - An American Symposium - RUSSIA #3, 1925 July (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Hindus, "The Russians-1962," NBC speech - RUSSIA #1, 1962 January 21 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Hindus speech, "Soviet Russia Today" - RUSSIA #2, 1938(?) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Hindus, "Writing on Russia" - RUSSIA #4, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Asia(magazine), 1927 April (Box 29, Folder 26)
      See page 297 for Hindus' article "The Russian Peasant Reborn."
    - Asia(magazine), 1927 December; 2 copies (Box 29, Folder 27)
      See page 983 for Hindus' article "The Jew in Revolutionary Russia."
    - The Outlook, 2 copies (Box 29, Folder 28)
      See page 280 for Hindus' article "Henry Ford Conquers Russia."
  - Changes in Russian life, undated
    - Hindus, "Agriculture in the USSR" - CHANGES #1, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Hindus, "Atheism-A Dying Crusade" - CHANGES #2, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Hindus - Modern Life in Moscow - CHANGES #3, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Hindus, "New Man-Fact or Fable?" - CHANGES #4, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Hindus, "Sex in the USSR" - CHANGES #5, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Hindus on Russia's split personality - CHANGES #6, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Hindus, "Nochleg"-Youth - CHANGES #7, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Book reviews by Hindus, 1951
    - Saturday Review of Literature, 1951 February 17-April 14; 2 items; 2 issues (Box 30, Folder 1)
      Includes Hindus' reviews of M.K. Argus'Moscow-on-the-Hudson and Vladimir Nabokov's Conclusive Evidence.
- Typed and handwritten notes, 1933-1968
  Topics include Svetlana, changes in Russian life, agriculture, Russia/Germany relations, interviews, people, and goverment business. Among the nations, regions, and cities discussed are Armenia, Czechoslovakia, Kuban, Persia, Prague, Praha, Russia, Siberia, and Yugoslavia.
  - 2 TN, Russia and Germany, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - TN, German authors in Soviet Russia, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - TN, Hitler speech, 1933 March 23 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - TN-Russia and Germany must fight, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - TN, Dinner with Gordienko, Russia/Germany relations, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - TN, Interview with Sobolenko, 1965 June 6 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - TN-Interview with V. Nezemtsev, 1965 June 8 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - TN, Interview with Pyotr Naumov; TN, Interview with Rotin, 1963 January 25 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - TN, Mayakovsky, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - TN, Nacko (pg. 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - TN, Khrushchev's troubles, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - TN, Khrushchev on Stalinism, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - TN,New York Times, 1960 March 14 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - AN, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - AN on Foreign Policy Association luncheon, 1933 February 4 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - AN, excerpt from Dr. Nicholas Butler's address to Columbia summer session, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - TN-problems in Communism, 1968 January-February (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - TN-Darrow and NRA, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - AN on Hilger, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - TN, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Times, newspaper bits, TC, [1938 or 1939] September 28 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - TN, Hindus, Profintern, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - TN, Should America recognize the Soviet Russian government?, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - TN, Columbia Broadcasting Company, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - AN, 1963 June 12-16 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - TN, Ilychev speech, 1963 June 18 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - TN, foreign influence in USSR, undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - TN, Suslov's address, 1964 June 2 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - TN, Hindus' response to articles in Pravda, Izvestia, Novy Mir, etc., undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - TN, Elks, undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - TN, "Russia Today", undated (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - TN, Odessa - RUSS #7, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - TN, arctic areas of Russia and Canada - SIBERIA #1, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - TN, Irkutsk, Siberia - SIBERIA #4, 1958 August 13 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - TN, Irkutsk University - SIBERIA #5, 1958 August 2 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - TN, Siberia (pg. 2) - SIBERIA #6, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - TN, Siberian Taiga - SIBERIA #7, no year July 29 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - TN, Yerevan, Armenia - ARM #1, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - TN, news from Czechoslovakia - CZECH #1, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - TN, Battle for Harvest in Czechoslovakia - CZECH #2, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - TN, Czechoslovakia press survey - CZECH #3, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - TN, AN, Miscellaneous from Czechoslovakia - CZECH #4, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - TN, Kuban - KUBAN #1, 1958 December 21 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - TN, Kuban - KUBAN #2, 1964 November 28 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - TN, Kiroukolhoz Kuban - KUBAN #3, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - TN, Cossack Kuban - KUBAN #4, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - TN, Isfahan - PERSIA #1, 1947 September 17 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - TN, Ramsar - PERSIA #2, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - TN, Tehran - PERSIA #3, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - TN, Prague - PRAGUE #1, no year July 23-27 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - TN, Prague - PRAGUE #2, 1963 July 23 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - TN, Prague (pg. 2) - PRAGUE #3, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - TN, observations of Klyn - PRAGUE #4, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - TN, News from Praha (German) - PRAHA #1, no year June 22 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - TN, news from Praha, AK 13-1-3 (German) - PRAHA #2, no year June 25-28 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - TN, Hindus, Ivanovo - RUSS #1, undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - TN, Kiev - RUSS #2, 1958 July 6-8 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - TN, Kiev to Minsk - RUSS #3, undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - TN, Krasnodar - RUSS #4, undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - TN, Leningrad - RUSS #5, undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - TN, Moscow - RUSS #6, undated (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - TN, Baikal - SIBERIA #2, no year August 2 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - TN, Garst and K - SIBERIA #3, undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Hindus, TL/TN(?), Yugoslavia - YUG #1, 1955 June 18 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - TN, G.I. Vorobyov, Party Agricultural Secretary, 1964 February (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Agricultural facts, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - TN, E. Novikov on agriculture, 1965 June 5 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - TN, FBI Agent Mr. Toole, 1950 December 20 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - TN, Soviet Union change in style and life, undated (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - TN, religion in USSR, undated (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - TN, Personality of New Man, 1963 June 20 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - TN, Observations, 1963 July 8 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - TN, Grishin and Kolbanovsky - Discussions on marriage or divorce, Hindus' response to Grishin, undated (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - TN on V. Sukhomlunsky's discussion of family, undated (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - TN, family, undated (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - AN, concerning birth control, marriage, religion, etc., undated (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - TN, G. Lisichkin - economist, undated (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - TN, product availability, 1965 June 8 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - TN, interview with Svetlana, 1967 April 22, 27 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - TN on Svetlana, undated (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - TN, Svetlana, undated (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - TN, random thoughts, 19?? July 25 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - TN, The World to Come, undated (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - TN, Brijesh Singh, undated (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Misc. TN and AN: Dr. Kroupa, Czechoslovakia, Tabor, religion, collectives, and military, undated (Box 14, Folder 57)
- Notes, interviews, and notebooks, 1910-1969
  - TN, Miscellaneous notes on North Brookfield, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - TN, interview with Mildred York, 1969 June 1 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - TN, interview with Alma Crumb, 1968 July 5, 1968 October 13 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - TN, interview with Alice, Muriel, and Susie Ramsdell, 1968 October 12 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - TN, interview with Dr. Robert Whitford, 1968 June 1 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - TN, interview with Dorothea Carey, 1969 April 28 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - TN, interview with Ed Walker, 1968 June 2 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - TN, interview with Lester Barnes, 1968 June 1 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - TN, Interview with Erwin Lambs, 1969 April 30, 1968 October 11 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - TN, interview with Clyde and Mildred Head, DeWitt and Carol Head, and Jack and June Head Fort, 1969 April 28 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - TN, interview with Irving Edgarton, 1969 April 27 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - TN, interview with Richard Pratt, 1968 May 31 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - TN, York Hill, 1969 June 1 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - TN, Interview with Bruce and Sally Barnes, 1969 May 30 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - TN-interview with John Grantin, 1968 June 1, 1968 October 13 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - TN, History of North Brookfield, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - AN, Hindus on American Council in Harbin, notebook, 1927 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - AN,New York Herald Tribune, Metropole Hotel, Moscow, notebook, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - AN, Munich crisis, notebook, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Date book/address book with various notes scattered throughout, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, notes on religion, minister sent to Russia, and need for a new replacement minister, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, description of Lithuania at Christmas and progressing farm tools, 1910-1930s (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, questions on conditions, patient environment, physical exam, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, notes on psychiatric condition of Edward and on various psychiatric conditions, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, notes on hospital, characterization of medical hierarchy and nursery school, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Notebook, time scale from early 1700s to late 1800s, subject: Russian/ German relations, land ownership, Bismark, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Notebook, notes on village life, info appears to be received from an interview, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Notebook, various notes and facts about Kolhozy, notes on AJ Root, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Notebook, various notes on different aspects of life in Yervan and other towns in Armenia and Odessa, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Notebook, notes on psychological conditions of Edward and his (the) behavioral patterns that coincided, notes on a few different psychological sicknesses, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Notebook, notes on various psychiatric illnesses and behavioral and environmental characteristics, notes on patient to doctor relations, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Notebook, interview with Dr. Hutchings on psychotherapy and psychology, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, notes on staff meeting attended by Hindus for hospital psychiatric staff and patients, ideas and problems expressed and recorded, 1950s (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, concerns and beliefs in and about the church in Soviet Union, 1800s-mid 1950s (primarily the latter), undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, various aspects of Kolhozy life specifically at the culmination of collectivization, includes people's responses, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Notebook, a variety of notes on Kolhozy and activities resulting from collectivization, agricultural facts (some are from Odessa), undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Notebook, listing of various agricultural crops existing-quantities and use, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Notebook, facts and figures on agricultural standings in Russia (crops...), 1950s-1960s (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Notebook, timeline of historical events, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Notebook, "M. Hindus, N.Y. Herald Tribune", undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Notebook, notes on rations, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Notebook, notes in Russian, notes on customs and people, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
- Novels and manuscript pieces, undated
  - Hindus, pages 1-50 Polish Novel, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Hindus, pages 51-100 Polish Novel, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Hindus, pages 101-150 Polish Novel, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Hindus, pages 151-200 Polish Novel, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Hindus, pages 201-250 Polish Novel, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Hindus, pages 251-300 Polish Novel, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Hindus, pages 301-350 Polish Novel, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Hindus, pages 351-400 Polish Novel, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Hindus, Final proof copy of Russia and Japan, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Hindus,Russia and Japan, pages 1-30, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Hindus,Russia and Japan, pages 31-60, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Hindus,Russia and Japan, pages 61-90, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Hindus,Russia and Japan, pages 91-120, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Hindus,Russia and Japan, pages 121-150, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Hindus,Russia and Japan, pages 151-180 (missing page 167), undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Hindus,Russia and Japan, pages 181-210 (missing pages 202-210), undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Hindus,Russia and Japan, pages 211-229 (missing 211-212), undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Hindus, Booklist, title page, chapter list, introduction by Milton Hindus for A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Hindus, pages 1-30, A Traveler in two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Hindus, pages 31-60,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Hindus, pages 61-90,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Hindus, pages 91-120,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Hindus, pages 121-150,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Hindus, pages 151-180,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Hindus, pages 181-210,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Hindus, pages 211-240,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Hindus, pages 241-270,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Hindus, pages 271-300,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Hindus, pages 301-330,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Hindus, pages 331-360,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Hindus, pages 361-390,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Hindus, pages 391-417,A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Hindus, Chapter 1, "The Letter," Upstate Novel, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Hindus, Chapter 2, Upstate Novel (adapted in part as ch. 2 "The Uprooted" for A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Hindus, Ch. III, Upstate Novel (adapted as Ch.2 "The Uprooted" for A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Hindus, Ch. IV, Upstate Novel (adapted as ch. 3 "A Land to Grow In" for A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Hindus, ch. 5, "Baptists," Upstate Novel (adapted as ch.5 "The Baptists" for A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Hindus, Ch. VI, Upstate Novel (adapted in part as ch.6 "Character and Characters" for A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Hindus, Ch. VII, "Character and Characters," Upstate Novel (adapted as Ch.6 "Character and Characters for A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Hindus, Ch. VIII, "Autumn," Upstate Novel (adapted as ch. 4 "Thanksgiving and Country Bounty" for A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Hindus, Ch. IX, "Rover," Upstate Novel, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Hindus, Ch. X, Upstate Novel (adapted as Ch. 7 "The Great Reward" for A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Hindus, Ch. XI, Upstate Novel (adapted at Ch. 8 "The Immigrant as Freshman" for A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Hindus, Ch. XII, Upstate Novel (adapted as Ch. 9 "Another America" for A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Hindus, Ch. XIII, Upstate Novel (adapted as Ch. 10 "The Campus Intelligentsia" for A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Hindus, Ch. XIV, "The Tailor Shop," Upstate Novel (adapted as Ch. 12 "The Tailor Shop," for A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Hindus, Ch. XV, Upstate Novel, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Hindus, Ch. XVII, "Sophomore," Upstate Novel (quoted pages 159-160 in A Traveler in Two Worlds), undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Hindus, Ch. VI, "The Monster Killer." pages 1-26, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Hindus, Ch. V?, pages 1-17, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Hindus, Chapter list, unpublished Svetlana, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Hindus, ch. I, "The Unknown Woman,"Svetlana, pages 1-14, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Hindus, ch. II, "Woman in the Limelight,"Svetlana, pages 1-11, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Hindus, Ch. IV, "Woman Naked,"Svetlana, pages 1-15, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Hindus, Ch. VI, "The Monster Killer,"Svetlana, pages 1-21, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Hindus, Ch. VII, "The Master Builder," pages 1-21, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Hindus, Corrections and Interpolations,Svetlana, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Hindus, Commentary on Siberian life - ch. 20 House Without a Roof, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Hindus, TC, "Siberia" - Ch. 21 House Without a Roof, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Hindus, "The Romance of Siberia" - Ch. 22 House Without a Roof, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Hindus, chapter list,The Kremlin's Human Dilemma, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Hindus, title page,The Kremlin's Human Dilemma, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Hindus, foreward,The Kremlin's Human Dilemma, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Hindus, Epilogue,The Kremlin's Human Dilemma, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Hindus, "Reflections on Russia and America," "Harvard," from A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Hindus, "Russia and Japan Must Fight," chapter list and title page, undated (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Hindus, various from A Traveler in Two Worlds, undated (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - To Sing with the Angels, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Green Worlds, manuscript piece, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Hindus, Autobiographical Incomplete (ch. III) page 36, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Hindus, Autobiographical Incomplete pages 44-59, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Hindus, "Christmas at Adams and at the Mansion", undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Hindus, Ch. VI, characters-Edward, Adam, Lillian, Katherine, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Hindus, "Foreward", undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Hindus, "Epilogue", undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Hindus, Ch. V, "The War of Values", undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Hindus, TC, Ch. IV, 11 pg, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Hindus, 2 TC, unidentified, ch. III, 24 pg, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Hindus, Ch. V, "Make Believe and Reality", missing 145-147, undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Hindus, corrections for page 125A, undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Hindus, page 264a, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Hindus, page 66a, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Hindus, page 30a, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Hindus page 389, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Hindus, page 389, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Hindus, page 373a, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Hindus, pages 180a-180b, undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Hindus, pages 383-389, undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Hindus, pages 107-107c and 43a-43d (same material), undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Hindus, pages 133a-133b, undated (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Hindus, pages 22-32, on Siberia, undated (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Hindus, pages 12-13, agricultural machines, undated (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Hindus, page 8, characters=Lillian and Edward, undated (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Hindus, pages 60-63, character=Madam Undset, undated (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Hindus, pages 4-8, on Siberia, undated (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Hindus, pages 2-5, Menhous Hitler/Germany, undated (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Hindus, "When Will the German people revolt?", undated (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Hindus, pages 2-4,Hitler Cannot Conquer Russia(?), undated (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Milton Hindus Manuscript, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified manuscript - pages/corrections, undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified manuscript pieces, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified manuscript pieces, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified manuscript pieces, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified manuscript, missing pages and title, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Hindus, pages unused and 103-105, Ch. VI, "At the Village Mill,"Broken Earth, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Hindus, Pages 184-203, Ch. X, "The Women Have Their Say,"Broken Earth, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Hindus, Pages 228-229, Ch. XI, "The Red Landlord,"Broken Earth, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Non-Hindus articles and speeches, 1926-1971
  - Newspaper, "Hindus, Back, See Soviety-Reich War,"New York Times, 1939 October 15 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper, "Hindus Began Career Writing for Observer," Utica, New York, 1940 February 7 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - "Letter to the Editor: Reaction to Hindus' Lecture", 1947 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Harry Elmer Barnes, Ph.D. "France's Trust in Britain", no year June (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper, "Hindus Sees Tragic Situation in Europe with war for Years,"Standard, 1940 February 6 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - ? written or translated by Hindus? "A New Day" (play), undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Hindus and Walter Duranty "Red Freedom" (a 3 act play), undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Hella Winolijoke, "Women of Property" (play), undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - John Strackey, "International Literature - Fascism and Culture", undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Milnes Levick, "this is the Master Race", undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Review of An American Tragedy by Theodore Dreiser, with notes, 1926 January 9 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - "Mythus," II. The Character of the New Religion, Rev. John Arendzen, M.A., D.D., 1936 September (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Vojta Benes "The Tragic Fate of Czechoslovakia," autographed and dated, 1940 March 20 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - 3 articles sent to Hindus by Jean Chalmers, 1940 February 15 (Box 26, Folder 14)